Guide to the Rose Rand Papers, 1903-1981 ASP.1990.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Rose Rand's Research Notes, Transcriptions, Manuscript Fragements, and Minutes, 1912-1978; VI.
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Ma-Re, 1940, 1978, and undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Ru-St, 1934, 1935, and undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Reading Notes and Summaries on Works by Authors Ta-Z, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Notes, Transcriptions, and Minutes: A-L, 1930, 1931, and undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Notes, Remarks, Transcriptions, and Summaries: M-Z, 1912-1921 and undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Research and Manuscript Fragments, 1930 and undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Research and Manuscript Fragments, 1930 and undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Research and Manuscript Fragments, 1930 and undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Research and Manuscript Fragments, 1930 and undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Subject-Related Notes and Analyses, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Wirklichkeit File, 1941-1943 and undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Proseminar, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Kotarbinski, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Wiener Kreis: Vorträge und Diskussion" and "Thesen", 1931-1932 and undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Notes on Gilbert Ryle, 1951, 1953, and undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ludwig Wittgenstein Lecture Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ludwig Wittgenstein's Blue Book, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ludwig Wittgenstein's Brown Book, 1934 -1935 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ludwig Wittgenstein's "Foundations of Mathematics", 1939 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Ludwig Wittgenstein Lectures, 1940, 1941, and undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Ludwig Wittgenstein, "Manuscripts I and II", 1934, 1950, and undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Notes and Transcriptions from Ludwig Wittgenstein Lectures and Writings, 1913, 1942, 1953, and undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Rose Rand's Writings about Ludwig Wittgenstein, 1971, 1972, and undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Rose Rand's Research on Sigmund Freud, 1973 and undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Rose Rand's Research on Sigmund Freud, 1973 and undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Rose Rand's Research on Sigmund Freud, 1973 and undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Rose Rand's Notebooks and Papers by Other Authors, 1913-1980; VII.
  Besides a few essays and abstracts by other writers and biographical sketches on individuals authored by Rose Rand, this series mainly comprises Rose Rand's notebooks. They contain a wide variety of entries, such as reading and research notes, book excerpts, bibliographic citations, translation drafts, name and address lists, telephone numbers, lists of her writings, Russian to English vocabulary, and some letter drafts.
  - Biographical Sketches, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Essays and Abstracts by other Writers, 1913, 1957, 1960, 1976, and undated (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
  - Shorthand Items, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Gabelsberger Shorthand Manual, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Rose Rand's Notebooks, 1951-1980, and undated (Box 12, Folder 6-21)
- Annotated Books from Rose Rand's Library, 1851-1970; VIII.
  The annotated books of Rose Rand's library were retained and integrated into the manuscript holdings. The books are arranged alphabetically by the author's last name.
  - Bavink,Bernhard. Ergebnisse und Probleme der Naturwissenschaft. Leipzig: S. Hirzel, 1924. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Lightly annotated; handwritten name of "Herbert Feigl" appears on first page of book and on verso of title page.
  - Carnap, Rudolf. Abriss der Logistik. Schriften zur wissenschaftlichen Weltanschauung Bd. 2. Vienna: Julius Springer, 1929. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Page-proofs, dated from 1929; lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand and author.
  - Carnap, Rudolf. Scheinprobleme in der Philosophie: Das Fremdpsychische und der Realismusstreit. Berlin-Schlachtensee: Weltkreisverlag, 1928. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Page-proofs; heavily annotated, apparently by Rose Rand and other hand; on book sleeve appears the handwritten note "Für Dr. Schächter."
  - Chwistek, Leon. Wielosc rzeczywistosci. Kraków: Ministerstwo W.R. I O.P., 1921 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Lightly annotated.
  - Egner, Robert E., ed. Bertrand Russell's Best: Silhouettes in Satire. New York: Mentor Books (New American Library of World Literature), 1961 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Eysenck, H. J. Uses and Abuses of Psychology. Harmondsworth: Penguin Books, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Falckenberg, Richard. Geschichte der neueren Philosophie von Nikolaus von Kues bis zur Gegenwart. Berlin: Walter de Gruyter (Vereinigung wissenschaftlicher Verleger), 1921 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Annotated, apparently by Rose Rand.
  - Gomperz, Heinrich. Weltanschauungslehre. Erster Band: Methodologie. Jena: Eugen Diederichs, 1905 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Grau, Kurt Joachim. Grundriß der Logik. Leipzig: B.G. Teubner, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Höfler, Alois. Propädeutische Logik für Realgymnasien und Reform-Realgymnasien. Leipzig: G. Freytag, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Jastrow, Joseph. Freud: His Dream and Sex Theories. (Originally titled The House that Freud Built). New York: Pocket Book, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Kant, Immanuel. Prolegomena zu einer jeden künftigen Metaphysik, die als Wissenschaft wird auftreten können. Leipzig: Reclam, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand.
  - Kaufmann, Felix. Das Unendliche in der Mathematik und seine Ausschaltung: Eine Untersuchung über die Grundlagen der Mathematik. Leipzig: F. Deuticke, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Page-proofs, dated 1929; lightly annotated, apparently by hand other than Rose Rand's.Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Czyn. Lwów: Polskie Towarzystwo Filozoficzne, 1934
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Czyn. Lwów: Polskie Towarzystwo Filozoficzne, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Elementy teorii poznania, logiki formalnej i metodologii nauk. Lwów: Wydawnictwo Zakladu Narodowego imienia Ossolinskich, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Heavily annotated, apparently by Rose Rand.
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Fragmenty filozoficzne. Warsaw: Nakladem Uczniów, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Rytmy i rymy. Warsaw: Czytelnik, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Lightly annotated; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author, dated 1970.
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Szkice praktyczne. Warsaw: E. Wende, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    No annotations; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author, dated 1937.
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Traktat o dobrej robocie. Wroclaw: Zaklad Narodowy im. Ossolinskich, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    Lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author, dated 1959.
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Utylitaryzm w etyce Milla i Spencera. Kraków: Nakladem Akademii Umiejetnosci, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    Lightly annotated; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author, dated 1936.
  - Kotarbinski, Tadeusz. Wyklady z dziejów logiki. Societas Scientiarum Lodziensis, Sectio 1, Nr. 28. Lódz: Zaklad Narodowy im. Ossolinskich we Wroclawiu, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    Annotated, apparently by Rose Rand; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author.
  - Kraft, Victor. Die Grundlagen einer wissenschaftlichen Wertlehre. Vienna: Julius Springer, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    Page-proofs; handwritten dedication to Rose Rand by author; lightly annotated, apparently by author and Rose Rand.
  - Külpe, Oswald. Vorlesungen über Logik. Leipzig: S. Hirzel, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    Heavily annotated, apparently by Rose Rand and by other hand; handwritten dedication by Mortiz Streit, dated 1924.
  - Le Bon, Gustave. The Crowd: A Study of the Popular Mind. New York: Ballantine, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Lecher, E. Lehrbuch der Physik für Mediziner, Biologen und Psychologen. Leipzig: B. G. Teubner, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Leibniz, G. W. Kleinere philosophische Schriften. Leipzig: Reclam, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Lindner, G. A., and Anton von Leclair. Lehrbuch der allgemeinen Logik. Für höhere Bildungsanstalten. Vienna: Carl Gerold's Sohn, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    Lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand and other hand; handwritten name of "Hugo Kasper" appears on title-page.
  - Lukasiewicz, Jan. Die logischen Grundlagen der Wahrscheinlichkeitsrechnung. Krakau: Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Lukasiewicz, Jan. Z zagadnien logiki i filozofii. Warsaw: Panstwowe Wydawnictwo Naukowe, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Nagel, Ernest, and James R. Newman. Gödel's Proof. New York: New York University Press, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Nietzsche, Friedrich. Der Wille zur Macht. Leipzig: Alfred Kröner, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Nietzsche, Friedrich. Zur Genealogie der Moral. Leipzig: Reclam, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Oppenheim, Paul. Die Denkfläche: Statische und dynamische Grundgesetze der wissenschaftlichen Begriffsbildung. Kant-Studien 62. Berlin-Charlottenburg: Pan-Verlag Kurt Metzner, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Lightly annotated; handwritten dedication to "Dir. Neurath" by author.
  - Philosophische Gesellschaft an der Universität zu Wien. Vorreden und Einleitungen zu klassischen Werken der Mechanik: Galilei, Newton, D'Alembert, Lagrange, Kirchhoff, Hertz, Helmholtz. Leipzig: C.E.M. Pfeffer, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Randolph, John F., and Mark Kac. Analytic Geometry and Calculus. New York: Macmillan, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand and other hand; handwritten name of "William Karusli"(?) appears on second page.
  - Reininger, Robert. Das Psycho-Physische Problem. Vienna: Wilhelm Braumüller, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Reininger, Robert. Kant: Seine Anhänger und seine Gegner. Munich: Ernst Reinhardt, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Rilke, Rainer Maria. Das Buch der Bilder. Leipzig: Im Insel-Verlag, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Lightly annotated; handwritten dedication by Horowitz Pepa.
  - Runes, Dagobert David. Der Jude und das Kreuz. Fürth: Ner-Tamid, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Ryle, Gilbert. The Concept of Mind. London: Hutchinson University Library, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Schächter, Josef. Prolegomena zu einer kritischen Grammatik. Vienna: Julius Springer, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Page-proofs, dated 1935; lightly annotated, apparently by Rose Rand.
  - Schlick, Moritz. Allgemeine Erkenntnislehre. Berlin: Julius Springer, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Lightly annotated, apparently by hand other than Rose Rand's.
  - Stallknecht, Newton P., and Robert S. Brumbaugh. The Spirit of Western Philosophy. New York: Longmans, Green and Co., 1954 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Stebbing, L. Susan. A Modern Elementary Logic. London: Methuen, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Tarski, Alfred. O logice matematycznei i metodzie dedukcyjnej. Biblioteczka matematyczna, 3-4-5. Lwów: Ksiaznica-Atlas, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Ueberweg, Friedrich. Grundriss der Geschichte der Philosophie des neunzehnten Jahrhunderts. Berlin: Ernst Siegfried Mittler und Sohn, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Whately, Richard D. D. Elements of Logic. Boston: James Munroe and Company, 1851 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Wolf, A. Textbook of Logic. London: George Allen and Unwin, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 21)